Jahidul Islam

44 Hampshire Avenue Bognor Regis West Sussex PO21 5JJ jahidul.pabel.islam@hotmail.com 07940970758

PERSONAL STATEMENT

As a young enthusiastic man, I always want and try to be the best at everything I do and always try to learn something new along the way. Applying for a Developer IT Placement at ARM because I would love the opportunity to expand my knowledge of Web Developing while gaining experience out in the real world as well as gaining life and web skills along the way.

EDUCATION

University of Portsmouth, BSc (Hons) Web Technologies, September 2014 – July 2018

Introduction to Programming

- Created a programme to display patches based on data inputted by a user using python language in IEP environment
- Created a programme using Java in DrJava environment

Web Foundation

 Constructed and tested a website using HTML5 incorporating my literature review and CV

Introduction to Database and Design

- Using a set of business rules I designed an Entity Relationship Diagram (ERD) using MySQL Workbench
- Created a database for a NHS prescription system case study using SQL

Computer Architecture

- Completed 2 logbooks of exercises in a study group about the hardware and software components of a computer system also the mathematical skills that relate to it
 - o Logic gates, Karnaugh maps, Binary numbers & Linux

Networking Fundamentals

- Completed a set of tasks about network topologies & hardware improvements independently as well as in groups
 - o Created a star topology network simulation on Riverbed Modeller
 - O Upgraded the Hard Disk Drive and RAM on a pc in groups
- Created a network design for a case study in groups with different aspects due in within in certain time frames

Chichester College, September 2012 – July 2014

- BTEC Extended Diploma, Distinction* Distinction
 E-Commerce
 - Designed, created, tested and evaluated an E-Commerce site selling console games using HTML

Client Side Customisation

o Used CSS to improve the look of my E-Commerce website

Server Scripting

o Used PHP to expand and enhance my E-Commerce site

Web Production

o Designed and created a Website promoting sports using HTML

Programming Fundamentals

 Designed and created an Programme for a shoe size converter using Visual Basic

Developing Computer Games

- o Designed, planned and created an Game using Visual Basic in a team
- Functional Skills English Level 2, Pass
- GCSE English Language, Grade D

The Regis School, Bognor Regis, September 2007 – July 2012

- 7 GCSEs B D:
- Diploma in Digital Applications (DiDA), Credit equivalent to 3 GCSE's. Covered Graphic Design, Games Design, & Using ICT

EMPLOYMENT

Team Member, KFC, Bognor Regis, August 2014 – November 2014

- Provided reliable, fast service
- Took orders from customers using my communication skills
- Used a till point, requiring numerical skills and knowledge of corporate systems
- Handled cash with care
- Handled customers' chip and pin cards
- Cleaned the kitchen & the front of house areas
- Made side orders
- Packed customers' orders
- Used my initiative to ensure that we were fully stocked

Waiter, Chilli (Takeaway), Littlehampton, June 2012 – September 2013

- Took customers' orders
- Used a till point
- Handled cash and card payments
- Packaged customers' orders

REFERENCES

References are available on request.

2015 IT Placement - Developer (1 year)

Job ID #: 5166

Country: UK Location: Cambridge

Job Category: Information Technology Employment Type: Students/Interns/Coops

Division: Administration Department: Information Technology

Hours of work (per week): 37.5

Apply Now

Job Description

Introduction

ARM is looking for a range of talented and enthusiastic students to spend their industrial placement year in our IT department

Developer IT Placement

ARM is looking for a range of talented and enthusiastic students to spend their industrial placement year in our IT department. Successful candidates will be assigned projects where they will have to capture requirements, fix problems, add new functionality, plan future improvements and document changes.

The developer industrial placement role within ARM IT is for candidates who wish to enhance their current skills in either software development or web development

We are interested in someone with enthusiasm, someone who can work with the talented IT team to create industry leading solutions to complex problems.

Within ARM, the IT group maintains and supports a wide range of services, applications and platforms to assist the business to achieve its corporate goals. Supporting such a diverse global business with demanding computing needs provides IT with an interesting and challenging work environment. IT has a great opportunity to investigate all of the various technologies and devices that are built around ARM's IP with the goal to implement them in the corporate environment.

Job Requirements

Are you a good fit for ARM?

The successful candidate should be able to demonstrate strong technical skills and will be in the 2nd year or later of an IT related degree or a recent graduate. The successful candidate should also have specific skills related to software or web development.

They will be self-motivated and able to work effectively on their own and as part of a team.

It is also important that the candidate has a passion for technology. They should be enthusiastic and keen to learn and further their skills.

Essential skills and experience that we are looking for include experience of at least one of:

Essential skills and experience that we are looking for include experience of at least one of:

- · C/C++/java/Python coding OR
- · Web Development Technologies eg. PHP, Perl, Javascript AND
- · Relational Database Fundamentals e.g. SQL, Indexes, Optimisation

Previous work experience within an IT or engineering environment would be an advantage, including experience in some of the following areas:

- · Computer Infrastructure
- OS Fundamentals
- · Linux & Unix Administration
- · Windows Administration
- · Troubleshooting Skills
- · Programming Skills
- · Software Development Methodologies
- · Database Administration
- · Networking Fundamentals
- · Security Fundamentals
- · Project Management Fundamentals

What's in it For You?

As an intern at ARM, you will work on real projects that have real impact, while also building on key skills for your future studies and employment. We believe in developing talent for the future, and therefore aim to offer many of our interns a graduate position once they have finished their studies.

Working on interesting new projects is exciting but we also know how important it is to receive support. That's why you will have regular 1 to 1 meetings with your line manager who will be able to offer ongoing support, feedback and development opportunities. You will be given a certain amount of flexibility and freedom in how you decide to complete your project tasks.

As well as being offered a competitive salary, there are also opportunities to get involved in some of the many social events that are organised within ARM.

About ARM

ARM® is at the heart of the world's most advanced digital products. Our technology enables the creation of new markets and transformation of industries and society. We design scalable, energy efficient-processors and related technologies to deliver the intelligence in applications ranging from sensors to servers, including smartphones, tablets, enterprise infrastructure and the Internet of Things.

Our innovative technology is licensed by ARM Partners who have shipped more than 50 billion Systems on Chip (SoCs) containing our intellectual property since the company began in 1990. Together with our Connected Community, we are breaking down barriers to innovation for developers, designers and engineers, ensuring a fast, reliable route to market for leading electronics companies.

With offices around the world, ARM is a diverse community of dedicated, innovative and highly talented professionals. By enabling an inclusive, meritocratic and open workplace where all our people can grow and succeed, we encourage our people to share their unique contributions to ARM's success in the global marketplace

http://careers.peopleclick.com/careerscp/client_arm/external/gateway.do?functionName=viewFromLink&jobPostId=17710&localeCode=en-us&sourceIndeed.com&sourceType=PREMIUM POST SITE